Guide to the Emil J. Dillon Papers, ca. 1873-1933
Department of Special Collections
- Series 3. Subjects and Events, 9 linear ft.
  - Subseries 5. Miscellaneous Materials
    - Miscellaneous Materials [7 of 27]1930 July 6 (Box 17, Folder 7)
    - Miscellaneous Materials [8 of 27]1907 Oct-Nov. (Box 17, Folder 8)
    - Miscellaneous Materials [9 of 27]Undated (Box 17, Folder 9)
    - Miscellaneous Materials [10 of 27]Undated (Box 17, Folder 10)
    - Miscellaneous Materials [11 of 27]Undated (Box 17, Folder 11)
    - Miscellaneous Materials [12 of 27]1917 Apr. 18 (Box 17, Folder 12)
    - Miscellaneous Materials [13 of 27]1884-1885 (Box 17, Folder 13)
      Includes a press cutting. Note: in Russian.
    - Miscellaneous Materials [14 of 27]1915 (Box 17, Folder 14)
      Includes maps. Note: in Spanish.
    - Miscellaneous Materials [15 of 27]1915 (Box 17, Folder 15)
      Note: in Spanish.
    - Miscellaneous Materials [16 of 27]1919 (Box 17, Folder 16)
    - Miscellaneous Materials [17 of 27]1920 (Box 17, Folder 17)
    - Miscellaneous Materials [18 of 27]Undated (Box 18, Folder 1)
      A map.
    - Miscellaneous Materials [19 of 27]Undated (Box 18, Folder 2)
    - Miscellaneous Materials [20 of 27]1909 Apr. (Box 18, Folder 3)
    - Miscellaneous Materials [21 of 27]1935 (Box 18, Folder 4)
    - Miscellaneous Materials [22 of 27]Undated (Box 18, Folder 5)
    - Miscellaneous Materials [23 of 27]Undated (Box 18, Folder 6)
    - Miscellaneous Materials [24 of 27]1932 (Box 18, Folder 7)
    - Miscellaneous Materials [25 of 27]1919 (Box 18, Folder 8)
    - Miscellaneous Materials [26 of 27]1904 Feb. (Box 18, Folder 9)
- Series 4. Articles, 3.5 linear ft.
  - A Band of Little Polish Martyrs1902 March [n.d.] (Box 1, Folder 1)
  - A Colourful KissUndated (Box 1, Folder 2)
    Includes typescripts.
  - A Comedy of MishapsUndated (Box 1, Folder 3)
  - A Duel with DestinyUndated (Box 1, Folder 4)
  - A Golden OpportunityUndated (Box 1, Folder 5)
    Includes typescripts. Refers to: Tchaikoffskii; Rubinstein.
  - A Russian Prince, Apostle, & ConvictUndated (Box 1, Folder 6)
    Includes a typescript. Refers to: Prince Khilkoff; Pobedonostseff.
  - AUnique Exhibition[No year] May 4 (Box 1, Folder 7)
    Includes an offprint.
  - AWonder-Working PhysicianUndated (Box 1, Folder 8)
  - An Arctic Christmas1907 Dec. 26; incl. undated materials (Box 1, Folder 9)
    Includes a clipping, a typescript.
  - An Austrian Sherlock HolmsUndated (Box 1, Folder 10)
  - After Three Years1917 Aug. 6-9 (Box 1, Folder 11)
    Includes offprints.
  - Allies1921 Sept. [n.d.] (Box 1, Folder 12)
  - Antonio Stoppani1900 Apr. [n.d.] (Box 1, Folder 13)
    Includes a press cutting. Refers to: Franz Xaver Kraus. Note: in German.
  - AphorismsUndated (Box 1, Folder 14)
  - Armenia1936 Apr.[?] (Box 1, Folder 15)
    Includes a press cutting. Refers to: M. Patkanoff; M. Dillon; Ch. L. Casartelli; D.L.O. Note: in French.
  - Articles Published in Daily Telegraph & Illustrated London News [1 of 9]1915 Dec. 26 (Box 1, Folder 16)
    Includes a descriptive list, offprints. Refers to: Greek King; the Kaiser; Queen Anne; King Henry IV; Nicholas II.
  - Articles Published in Daily Telegraph & Illustrated London News [2 of 9]1916 Jan. 11 (Box 1, Folder 17)
  - Articles Published in Daily Telegraph & Illustrated London News [3 of 9]1916 July 20 - 1917 June 22; incl. undated materials (Box 1, Folder 18)
  - Articles Published in Daily Telegraph & Illustrated London News [4 of 9]1914[?] - 1917[?] (Box 1, Folder 19)
  - Articles Published in Daily Telegraph & Illustrated London News [5 of 9]1917 July 2 - July 9 (Box 1, Folder 20)
  - Articles Published in Daily Telegraph & Illustrated London News [6 of 9]1917 July 13; incl. undated materials (Box 1, Folder 21)
  - Articles Published in Daily Telegraph & Illustrated London News [7 of 9]1918 June 28 (Box 1, Folder 22)
  - Articles Published in Daily Telegraph & Illustrated London News [8 of 9]1918 July 22 (Box 1, Folder 23)
  - Articles Published in Daily Telegraph & Illustrated London News [9 of 9]1916 [n.d.] - 1916 [Jan./Feb.] (Box 1, Folder 24)
  - Baron Aehrenthal and M. Izvolskii1909 Sept. - Nov. [n.d.]; incl. undated materials (Box 2, Folder 1)
    Includes press cuttings, a typescript..
  - Beginning of Article (Plan)Undated (Box 2, Folder 2)
  - Belgian CongoUndated (Box 2, Folder 3)
  - BolshevismUndated (Box 2, Folder 4)
    Includes notes. Refers to: Lenin.
  - Bulgaria [1 of 3]1908 Dec. [n.d.] (Box 2, Folder 5)
    Includes: a descriptive list, a typescript, press cuttings, offprints. Refers to: Prince Ferdinand of Bulgaria; Stambuloff; the Kaiser; the Sultan; Baron Von Aehrenthal..
  - Bulgaria [2 of 3]1908 Nov. [n.d.] (Box 2, Folder 6)
  - Bulgaria [3 of 3]1918 [June-Aug.?] [n.d.] (Box 2, Folder 7)
  - Catholicism versus Ultramotanism1902 Dec. [n.d.] (Box 2, Folder 8)
  - Clue to Servia's PolicyUndated (Box 2, Folder 9)
  - Constitutional Russia [1 of 4]Undated (Box 2, Folder 10)
    Includes typescripts, notes. Refers to: Stolypin; P.N. Durnovo; Count Witte.
  - Constitutional Russia [2 of 4][No year] Apr. 28 (Box 2, Folder 11)
  - Constitutional Russia [3 of 4]Undated (Box 2, Folder 12)
  - Constitutional Russia [4 of 4]Undated (Box 2, Folder 13)
  - Conversation with Giers - Misunderstanding Between Austria & Russia[No year] March 17 (Box 2, Folder 14)
  - Convict Life in Siberia Under the TsarUndated (Box 2, Folder 15)
  - Count Leo Tolstoi1901 March 14 (Box 2, Folder 16)
  - Christmas Eve in a Motor CabUndated (Box 2, Folder 17)
  - DefinitionsUndated (Box 2, Folder 18)
  - Diamond Cut DiamondUndated (Box 2, Folder 19)
  - Dillon's Last Article [1 of 2]1933 Apr. 7 - Apr. 10 (Box 2, Folder 20)
    Includes tls, notes, typescripts. Refers to: Roosevelt; Curtius; Mussolini; Wilson; Poincare; H.R. Westwood, Esq.; Nicholas II.
  - Dillon's Last Article [2 of 2]Undated (Box 2, Folder 21)
  - Europe of Today. In Quest of Money and a Man.Undated (Box 2, Folder 22)
    Includes typescripts. Refers to: Poincare; Herriot; Hindenburg; Benesch; Cailaux; Chamberlain.
  - Europe in Flux1925 [n.d.] (Box 2, Folder 23)
  - European Conditions - War in Peace1921 Sept. [n.d.] (Box 2, Folder 24)
  - Extracts form the Anual Register1896 [n.d.] (Box 2, Folder 25)
    Includes notes. Refers to: the Czar; the Czarina; Emperor Francis Joseph; Prince Lobanoff; Count Goluchowski; the German Emperor; M. Shishikin.
  - Fate in its Russian DressUndated (Box 2, Folder 26)
  - Forecast of Russian Revolution1912 Apr. 23 - May 6 (Box 2, Folder 27)
  - Foreign Affairs - Contemporary Review [1 of 6]Undated (Box 2, Folder 28)
    Includes descriptive lists, typescripts, press cuttings.
  - Foreign Affairs - Contemporary Review [2 of 6]1912 Jan. [n.d.] (Box 2, Folder 29)
  - Foreign Affairs - Contemporary Review [3 of 6]1912 Jan. - Feb. [n.d.] (Box 2, Folder 30)
  - Foreign Affairs - Contemporary Review [4 of 6]1912 March - May [n.d.] (Box 2, Folder 31)
  - Foreign Affairs - Contemporary Review [5 of 6]1912 June - Sept. [n.d.] (Box 2, Folder 32)
  - Foreign Affairs - Contemporary Review [6 of 6]1912 Nov. Dec. [n.d.] (Box 2, Folder 33)
  - Foreign OfficeUndated (Box 2, Folder 34)
  - Free MasonryUndated (Box 2, Folder 35)
    Includes a typescript. Note: in French.
  - Fortnightly Review - E.J. Dillon's Articles [1 of 15]1894 Jan [n.d.] - 1898 Jan. [n.d.] (Box 3, Folder 1)
    Includes: press cuttings, offprints, notes, an inventory.
  - Fortnightly Review - E.J. Dillon's Articles [2 of 15]1902 March [n.d.] - 1909 Sept.[n.d.] (Box 3, Folder 2)
  - Fortnightly Review - E.J. Dillon's Articles [3 of 15]1910 Apr. 7 - June [n.d.] (Box 3, Folder 3)
  - Fortnightly Review - E.J. Dillon's Articles [4 of 15]1915 May 1 - Nov.[n.d.] (Box 3, Folder 4)
  - Fortnightly Review - E.J. Dillon's Articles [5 of 15]1915 Dec. 10 - 1916 Jan. [n. d.] (Box 3, Folder 5)
  - Fortnightly Review - E.J. Dillon's Articles [6 of 15]1915 Jan. 18 - Feb. [n.d.] (Box 3, Folder 6)
  - Fortnightly Review - E.J. Dillon's Articles [7 of 15]1916 March 1 - May 1 (Box 3, Folder 7)
  - Fortnightly Review - E.J. Dillon's Articles [8 of 15]1916 July [n.d.] (Box 3, Folder 8)
  - Fortnightly Review - E.J. Dillon's Articles [9 of 15]1916 Sept. 1 - Oct. 2 (Box 3, Folder 9)
  - Fortnightly Review - E.J. Dillon's Articles [10 of 15]1916 Oct. 17 - Nov. [n.d.] (Box 3, Folder 10)
  - Fortnightly Review - E.J. Dillon's Articles [11 of 15]1916 Nov. 30 - 1917 Jan. [n.d.] (Box 3, Folder 11)
  - Fortnightly Review - E.J. Dillon's Articles [12 of 15]1917 Jan. [n.d.] - Feb. [n.d.] (Box 3, Folder 12)
  - Fortnightly Review - E.J. Dillon's Articles [13 of 15]1917 March [n.d.] - June [n.d.] (Box 3, Folder 13)
  - Fortnightly Review - E.J. Dillon's Articles [14 of 15]1917 July 2 - Sept. [n.d.] (Box 3, Folder 14)
  - Fortnightly Review - E.J. Dillon's Articles [15 of 15]1917 Oct. 1 - Dec. [n.d.] (Box 3, Folder 15)
  - Forty Years of Diplomacy - by RoserUndated (Box 3, Folder 16)
    Includes a typescript. Refers to: Dr. Dillon; Alexander II; Nelidoff; Pobedonostsev; Witte; Sir Donald Mckenzie Wallace; Mr. Hedeman; Signor Cortesi.
  - From Vanity Vellum PadUndated (Box 3, Folder 18)
  - FuchsUndated (Box 3, Folder 19)
    Includes tls. Note: in German.
  - Galicia - Western Ukraine1921 July 20; incl. undated materials (Box 3, Folder 20)
    Includes typescripts. Note: in Russian.
  - General CriticismUndated (Box 3, Folder 21)
  - GreeceUndated (Box 3, Folder 22)
    Includes notes. Refers to: Venizelos; King Constantine.
  - History of the Treaty of PortsmouthUndated (Box 3, Folder 23)
    Includes a typescript. Refers to: Lamsdorff; Witte; Muravieff; Baron Rosen; the Emperor; Roosevelt; Pokotiloff.
  - HitlerUndated (Box 3, Folder 24)
    Includes notes. Refers to: MacDonald.
  - How Detective Brausewetter Overplayed His HandUndated (Box 3, Folder 25)
  - Illusions of the Belligerents1918 July [n.d.] (Box 3, Folder 26)
    Refers to: President Wilson; the Kaiser.
  - Italy's Present Condition and OutlookUndated (Box 3, Folder 27)
  - Japan1907 May 12; incl. undated materials (Box 3, Folder 28)
    Includes a typescript, tls. Refers to: Kuropatkin; Bezobrazoff; Philander Knox; Sun Yat Sen.
  - Japan & Russia. A Fateful ProposalUndated (Box 3, Folder 29)
  - JewsUndated (Box 4, Folder 1)
    Includes a typescrip, an offprint, notes. Refers to: Witte; the Tsar; Roosevelt; Bulyghin; Gen. Trepoff; Durnovo; Sakhoroff[?]; Avellan; Manakhen; Lamsdorf; Kokofftseff; the Grand Duke Alexander Mikhailivitch; Gourykin; Stolypin.
  - Jewish Colonisation and the Russian Persecution1891 Aug. [n.d.] (Box 4, Folder 2)
  - Jews and the Vatican1905 Apr. 24 - 1916 Apr. 17 (Box 4, Folder 3)
    Includes a press cutting, a typescript. Note: a typescript is in French.
  - Kaiser Wilhelm1905 June 30 - 1926 Feb. 4 (Box 4, Folder 4)
    Includes a press cutting, notes, offprints.. Note: a press cutting is in German.
  - Labor and SocialismUndated (Box 4, Folder 5)
  - Lamsdorff, Vladimir Nikolaievich, CountUndated (Box 4, Folder 6)
  - League of NationsUndated (Box 4, Folder 7)
  - Liberty of ConscienceUndated (Box 4, Folder 8)
    Includes a typescript. Refers to: the Tsar; Stolypin; Ignatieff.
  - Mendicity, Mendacity and MarriageUndated (Box 4, Folder 9)
  - Mexico's New BirthUndated (Box 4, Folder 10)
  - Mine and CountermineUndated (Box 4, Folder 11)
  - MoscowUndated (Box 4, Folder 12)
    Includes a typescript. Refers to: Ivan the Terrible.
  - My impressions of Journalism in RussiaUndated (Box 4, Folder 13)
  - My Talk with a Devil-WorshipperUndated (Box 4, Folder 14)
    Includes a typescript, notes.
  - New Wars for OldUndated (Box 4, Folder 15)
    Includes a typescript, notes. Refers to: State Secretary Stimson; the Kaiser; Sun Yat Sen; President Roosevelt; the Tsar; Li Hung Chang; Viscount Hayashi; Alexeyeff; Bezobrazoff; Kuropatkin.
  - Nihilism in Contemporary Russian Literature1910 Oct. [n.d.] (Box 4, Folder 16)
    Includes an offprint. Refers to: Pushkin; Lermontoff; Goncharoff; Dostoieffskii; Tolstoi; Gorkii; Artzybasheff; Andreieff.
  - North American Review - E.J. Dillon's Articles [1 of 12]1904 Aug. [n.d.] - Dec. [n.d.] (Box 4, Folder 17)
    Includes an inventory.
  - North American Review - E.J. Dillon's Articles [2 of 12]1905 May [n.d.] - July [n.d.] (Box 4, Folder 18)
  - North American Review - E.J. Dillon's Articles [3 of 12]1905 Sept. [n.d.] - Dec. [n.d.] (Box 4, Folder 19)
  - North American Review - E.J. Dillon's Articles [4 of 12]1906 Jan. [n.d.] - June [n.d.] (Box 4, Folder 20)
  - North American Review - E.J. Dillon's Articles [5 of 12]1906 June [n.d.] - Dec. [n.d.] (Box 4, Folder 21)
  - North American Review - E.J. Dillon's Articles [6 of 12]1907 Feb. [n.d.] - Apr. 19 (Box 4, Folder 22)
  - North American Review - E.J. Dillon's Articles [7 of 12]1907 June 21 -Aug. 16 (Box 4, Folder 23)
  - North American Review - E.J. Dillon's Articles [8 of 12]1907 Oct. [n.d.] - Dec. [n.d.] (Box 4, Folder 24)
  - North American Review - E.J. Dillon's Articles [9 of 12]1908 Jan. [n.d.] -March [n.d.] (Box 4, Folder 25)
  - North American Review - E.J. Dillon's Articles [10 of 12]1908 Apr. [n.d.] -Nov. [n.d.] (Box 4, Folder 26)
  - North American Review - E.J. Dillon's Articles [11 of 12]1908 Apr. [n.d.] - July [n.d.] (Box 4, Folder 27)
  - North American Review - E.J. Dillon's Articles [12 of 12]1908 Aug. [n.d.] - Dec. [n.d.] (Box 4, Folder 28)
  - Notes for Political CurrentsUndated (Box 4, Folder 29)
  - Notes from Purple Vellum PadUndated (Box 4, Folder 30)
    Includes notes. Refers to: Mr. McDonald; Dr. Curtius.
  - Notes to Memoirs [1 of 9]Undated (Box 5, Folder 1)
    Includes notes, typescripts.
  - Notes to Memoirs [2 of 9]Undated (Box 5, Folder 2)
  - Notes to Memoirs [3 of 9]Undated (Box 5, Folder 3)
  - Notes to Memoirs [4 of 9]Undated (Box 5, Folder 4)
  - Notes to Memoirs [5 of 9]1933 (Box 5, Folder 5)
  - Notes to Memoirs [6 of 9]Undated (Box 5, Folder 6)
  - Notes to Memoirs [7 of 9]Undated (Box 5, Folder 7)
  - Notes to Memoirs [8 of 9]Undated (Box 5, Folder 8)
  - Notes to Memoirs [9 of 9]Undated (Box 5, Folder 9)
  - Notes - Unused in Peasants Undated (Box 5, Folder 10)
  - On RussiaUndated (Box 5, Folder 11)
    Includes a typescript Note: in German.
  - Opinion of... - On British Constitutional Crisis1911 [n.d.] (Box 5, Folder 12)
  - Opinion of Prince Sabat EddineUndated (Box 5, Folder 13)
    Includes a typescript. Refers to: the Sultan of Turkey.
  - Pagan Virtue1893 Jan. [n.d.] (Box 5, Folder 14)
  - ParalipomenaUndated (Box 5, Folder 15)
  - PersiaUndated (Box 5, Folder 16)
    Includes typescripts, notes. Refers to: the Shah; Emir Bakhdur Djenk; Novakovitch; Aehrenthal.
  - Personal Relations with Sazonoff1913 May 8-21 (Box 5, Folder 17)
  - Pessimism & Optimism in PoliticsUndated (Box 5, Folder 18)
  - Plot and CounterplotUndated (Box 5, Folder 19)
  - PobedonostseffUndated (Box 5, Folder 20)
    Includes a typescript. Refers to: the Tsar; Thomas Cromwell; Count Tolstoi.
  - Portugal [1a of 3]1910 Oct. 6 (Box 5, Folder 21)
    Includes notes, press cuttings. Refers to: Moret; King Manuel. Note: some materials are in French.
  - Portugal [1b of 3]1910 Oct. 10 - Oct. 13 (Box 5, Folder 22)
  - Portugal [1c of 3]1910 Oct. 17; incl. undated materials (Box 5, Folder 23)
  - Portugal [2 of 3]1910 Nov. 4 - 1925 [n.d.]; incl. undated materials (Box 5, Folder 24)
  - Portugal [3 of 3]Undated (Box 5, Folder 25)
  - Present Political Currents1924[?] [n.d.] (Box 5, Folder 26)
  - Reaction, Liberty, or License in Russia1906 Feb. 10 (Box 5, Folder 27)
  - Reorganisation of Army and PoliceUndated (Box 5, Folder 28)
    Includes a typescript Refers to: Alexander II; Miliutin; Paskievitch; Trepoff.
  - Revelations from the Abyss1902 Jan. [n.d.] (Box 5, Folder 29)
  - Review of Reviews - Contents Needed for ArticleUndated (Box 5, Folder 30)
    Includes notes. Refers to: Izzet Pasha; Iamal Kemal Bey; Prince Wied; Essad; King Peter of Sevia; Delcasse; Viviani; Thompson; the Kaiser; Edward Grey; Venizelos; King Carol; Giuliano; Ferdinand of Roumania.
  - Russia - ContrastsUndated (Box 5, Folder 31)
  - Russia and China1912 Apr. 4 (Box 5, Folder 32)
  - Russia's Awakening1917 May 2 [3/5?] (Box 5, Folder 33)
  - Russian Prisons Undated (Box 5, Folder 34)
  - Russian Revolution & Russian Literature [1 of 3] 1908 Feb. 27; incl. undated materials (Box 5, Folder 35)
    Includes typescripts, notes. Refers to: Muravieff; Alexander II; Witte; Lamsdorff; Kuropatkin; Nicholas Gay; Artsybasheff; Aristophanes; Catullus; Krinitskii; Yaroshenko; Turghenieff; Stolypin.
  - Russian Revolution & Russian Literature [2 of 3] Undated (Box 5, Folder 36)
  - Russian Revolution & Russian Literature [3 of 3] Undated (Box 5, Folder 37)
  - Russian Revolution Appendix - Details of the Secret TreatyUndated (Box 5, Folder 38)
  - Russian Scheme on the BosphorusUndated (Box 5, Folder 39)
    Includes a typescript. Refers to: Nelidoff; the Kaiser; Pobedonostseff; Queen Victoria; Lobanoff-Rostoffskii; Shishkin; the Tsar; Prince Ukhtomskii; Witte; the Sultan.
  - Schools Not EvolutionaryUndated (Box 5, Folder 40)
  - Scecond Article on Far EastUndated (Box 5, Folder 41)
    Includes a typescript Refers to: Viscount Hayashi; Witte; President Roosevelt.
  - Sectairans and Money -Changers1933 Nov. [n.d.] (Box 5, Folder 42)
    Includes a clipping.
  - ServiaUndated (Box 5, Folder 43)
    Includes a typescript. Refers to: King Peter; Count Aehrenthal; Count Berchtold; the Tsar.
  - Serbia after Murder of AlexanderUndated (Box 5, Folder 44)
  - Shadow of War1914 July 27 (Box 5, Folder 45)
  - StambuloffUndated (Box 5, Folder 46)
    Includes a typescript Refers to: Petkoff; Prince Ferdinand; the Russian Tsar; the Kaiser Franz Josef.
  - Summary of Telegrams for April Foreign Affairs Article[No year] Apr.[?] 4/17 - Apr.[?] 20/May[?] 4 (Box 5, Folder 47)
    Includes notes. Refers to: Prince Urusoff; Grand Duke Nicholas; Stolypin; Calvini; the Tsar; Sir E. Grey; Kaiser Wilhelm; the Sultan; Gen. Ivanoff; Baron Aehrenthal; Prince Bulow.
  - Syria1913 June 13 (Box 6, Folder 1)
  - T.P.O.C. on Dr. Dillon's Article 19161916 Feb. [n.d.] (Box 6, Folder 2)
    Includes a press cutting. Refers to: Signor Salandra; Baron Sonnino; Signor Giolitti; Prince von Bulow.
  - The English Bank in Russia19[09/10?] [n.d.] (Box 6, Folder 3)
  - The Entente - General NotesUndated (Box 6, Folder 4)
  - The Girl He Left Behind Him Undated (Box 6, Folder 5)
  - The Insurrection in ArabiaUndated (Box 6, Folder 6)
  - The Last Act1917 Feb. 1 (Box 6, Folder 7)
  - The Last of the RussiansUndated (Box 6, Folder 8)
    Includes a typescript Refers to: Sazomoff..
  - The Law & the ProverbsUndated (Box 6, Folder 9)
    Includes a typescript
  - The New Situation1916 Oct. [n.d.] (Box 6, Folder 10)
  - The Newly-Married Couple Shut OutUndated (Box 6, Folder 11)
  - The Nineteenth Century: E.J. Dillon's Articles1909 Aug. - 1912 Oct. [n.d.] (Box 6, Folder 12)
    Includes a descriptive list, press cuttings.
  - The Papal Encyclical on the Bible1894 Apr. [n.d.] (Box 6, Folder 13)
    Includes a typescript, a press cuting, notes.
  - The Paris ConferenceUndated (Box 6, Folder 14)
  - The Poem of JobUndated (Box 6, Folder 15)
  - The Primitive Gospel1893 June [n.d.] (Box 6, Folder 16)
  - The Russian Problem: is Goverment by Duma Possible?1906 Nov. 1 (Box 6, Folder 17)
  - The ScapegoatUndated (Box 6, Folder 18)
    Includes typescripts Refers to: Paul Morozoff.
  - The Third Duma1907 Dec. [n.d.] (Box 6, Folder 19)
    Includes typescripts Refers to: Stolypin; the Tsar; A.I. Goochkoff; Miliukoff; Kokovtseff.
  - The Truth About Baron Marschall Von Bieberstein[No year] June 27 (Box 6, Folder 20)
    Includes a typescript. Refers to: Abdul Hamid; Hakki Pasha; the Kaiser; Talaat Bey.
  - The Tsar's Eirenicon1898 Nov. [n.d.] (Box 6, Folder 21)
  - The TurksUndated (Box 6, Folder 22)
    Includes typescripts. Refers to: Said Pasha; Kiamil Pasha; Abdul Hamid; Prince Sabah Eddin.
  - The Western Peace-Makers in the Far EastUndated (Box 6, Folder 23)
    Includes a typescript, notes. Refers to: Viscount Hayashi; Izvolskii; Li Hung Chang; Count Witte; Prince Obolenskii; Meyer; Rockhill; Pavloff; Gen. Cheng Kai Shek.
  - Three Xmas EvesUndated (Box 6, Folder 24)
  - Thunder in Their Veins, a Memoir of Mexico - by Leone B. MoatsUndated (Box 6, Folder 25)
    Includes a typescript. Refers to: Gen. Obregon.
  - Travels in RussiaUndated (Box 6, Folder 26)
    Includes a typescript. Refers to: Tsar Paul.
  - Turning Point of the War - On the Eve [1 of 5]1916 Dec. [n.d.] - 1917 Jan. [n.d.] (Box 6, Folder 27)
    Includes offprints. Refers to: Le Sage; Lloyd George; Viviani; Briand; Delcasse; Venizelos; Bratiani; Count Czermin; the Kaiser..
  - Turning Point of the War - On the Eve [2 of 5]1916[?] Dec. 16 (Box 6, Folder 28)
  - Turning Point of the War - On the Eve [3 of 5]Undated (Box 6, Folder 29)
  - Turning Point of the War - On the Eve [4 of 5]Undated (Box 6, Folder 30)
  - Turning Point of the War - On the Eve [5 of 5][1917?] Jan. 10 (Box 6, Folder 31)
  - Two Years of War [1 of 3]Undated (Box 7, Folder 1)
    Includes typescritps, a letter, tls. Refers to: Le Sage; Count Witte; Giolitti; the Tsar; Jonescu; Bratiani; the Kaiser; King Constantine; Gen. Staff; Gen. Joffre; King Albbert; Gen. Polivanoff; Baron Sonnino; Nicholas I; Sazonoff; Sir Francis Elliot; Guillemin; Venizelos; Mr. Lloyd George; M. Briand; King Ferdinand; M. Zographos; the Queen of Greece; Mr. Miller; William II; Mr. Hughes; Nicholas II; M. Viviani; the King of the Belgians; King Carol; Peter Carp; Alexander Marghiloman; Maiorescu.
  - Two Years of War [2 of 3]1916 Aug. 4; incl. undated materials (Box 7, Folder 2)
  - Two Years of War [3 of 3]Undated (Box 7, Folder 3)
  - Unpublished part of the letter to N.A.R.1908 Jan [n.d.] (Box 7, Folder 4)
  - Untitled [1 of 10]Undated (Box 7, Folder 5)
    Includes notes, typescripts, a manuscript. Refers to: the Pope; Loisy; Arbishop Mignot; Arch. Richard; Cardinal Galimberti; Mathieu; Gibbons; Ferd. Brunetiere; Monsgr. d'Hulst; Abbe Icard; Bacuez; Duchesne; Vigouroux; Padre Genocchi; F.X. Kaus; Prof. Schell; Andreieff; Ukhtomskii; Alexeyeff; the Tsar; Count Witte; Stolypin; Theotokis; Rhallis; Colonel Lapathiote; Navromichalis; Ling; Pres. Roosevelt; Mr. Ramsay; McDonald. Nore: some materials are in French, Spanish.
  - Untitled [2 of 10][No year] June 10 (Box 7, Folder 6)
  - Untitled [3 of 10]Undated (Box 7, Folder 7)
  - Untitled [4 of 10]Undated (Box 7, Folder 8)
  - Untitled [5 of 10]Undated (Box 7, Folder 9)
  - Untitled [6 of 10]Undated (Box 7, Folder 10)
  - Untitled [7 of 10]1908 [n.d.] -June [n.d.] (Box 7, Folder 11)
  - Untitled [8 of 10]Undated (Box 7, Folder 12)
  - Untitled [9 of 10]Undated (Box 7, Folder 13)
  - Untitled [10 of 10]1919 June 4 (Box 7, Folder 14)
  - U.S.A.1933 Apr. 22; incl.undated materials (Box 7, Folder 15)
    Includes notes, a press cutting. Refers to: Mr. Roosevelt; Mr. Stimson. Note: a press cutting is in Spanish.
  - Various Contemporary Review Articles - Papacy & Religion [1 of 5]1893 Apr. [n.d.] (Box 7, Folder 16)
    Includes press cuttings. Refers to: the Pope.
  - Various Contemporary Review Articles - Papacy & Religion [2 of 5]1893 May 15 - June [n.d.] (Box 7, Folder 17)
  - Various Contemporary Review Articles - Papacy & Religion [3 of 5]1894 Apr. [n.d.] (Box 7, Folder 18)
  - Various Contemporary Review Articles - Papacy & Religion [4 of 5]1894 Aug. [n.d.]; incl. undated materials (Box 7, Folder 19)
  - Various Contemporary Review Articles - Papacy & Religion [5 of 5]1894 Sept. [n.d.] - 1907 [n.d.]; incl. undated materials (Box 7, Folder 20)
  - WarUndated (Box 7, Folder 21)
    Includes notes. Refers to: Napoleon.
  - Weyler1898 May 10 (Box 7, Folder 22)
    Includes a press cutting. Note: in Spanish.
  - What the Shah Think - Russia & Persia1889 July 9 - 1900 Jan. 10 (Box 7, Folder 23)
    Includes a press cutting, an offprint.